Guide to the National Student Christian Federation Records
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Program Committees, Series VIII
  - Committee on Christian Work Among International Students
    The Committee on Chrisitian Work Among International Students was originally lodged in the USCC, and carried over into the NSCF. It served as an advisory committee for interdenominational ministries to international students at several universities including University of Michigan, University of Chicago, University of California in L.A., Washington, D.C., Columbia University, University of California at Berkeley, and MIT. Some of the groups advised went on to become ecumenical ministries on their campuses with dedicated staff. They published the manual Resource and Reflection. The CCWAIS also conducted seminars, workshops, and consultations concerning training for working with international students, and specific areas of concerns such as the situations in Africa. CCWAIS assisted in recruiting foreign student involvement for the 19th Quadrennial. The African Student Emergency Aid Program was lodged under this committee. The Aid Program sought to reach out to African students to provide assistance in scholarship grants, job placement, and housing. The CCWAIS also worked with other committees in the NSCF such as the Southern Africa and the Latin American Concerns committees as their work overlapped with each other. Records in this subseries entail correspondence, minutes, reports, and information about the Ecumenical International Ministries at various universities.
    - General Committee Records
      - Advisory Committee for African Students' Emergency Aid Program: Memos and minutes, 1961 (Box 41, Folder 522)
      - African Students' Emergency Aid Program: Publications and reports, 1960-1962 (Box 41, Folder 523)
      - CC letters from campus ministries re. International Student programs, 1962 (Box 41, Folder 524)
      - Committee meeting: Docket, minutes, and reports, March 1-3, 1963 (Box 41, Folder 525)
      - Committee meeting: Agenda, minutes, and reports, April 1-3, 1966 (Box 41, Folder 526)
      - Consultation minutes: Mill Valley Consultation on the Christian Ministry to International Students, Consultation on Developing Ecumenical Ministry Among the International Community on United States Campuses, 1960, 1965 (Box 41, Folder 527)
      - Correspondence, Gerhard Elston to Baltimore groups, 1964-1965 (Box 41, Folder 528)
      - Development of International Ministry on U.S. Campuses, 1966 (Box 41, Folder 529)
      - Directory, 1965, 1966, undated (Box 41, Folder 530)
      - Ecumenical Ministries Sub-Committee minutes, 1966 (Box 41, Folder 531)
      - Five Year Experimental Program in Ecumenical Ministry in the State of Michigan includes publications and reports, 1965-1966 (Box 41, Folder 532)
      - Full committee memos and minutes, 1959-1961 (Box 41, Folder 533)
      - Full committee memos and minutes, 1962-1966 (Box 42, Folder 534)
      - Memos, 1964-1965, undated (Box 42, Folder 535)
      - National Training Seminar for Christian Workers Among International Students: Evaluations and hand outs from workshops, 1961 (Box 42, Folder 536)
      - National Training Seminar for Christian Workers Among International Students: Promotional materials and correspondence re. programming for event, 1961 (Box 42, Folder 537)
      - Organizations involved in assisting international students, 1960-1961 (Box 42, Folder 538)
      - Proposals: Regional "Continuing Education" Consultations for Campus Ministry Personnel, Development Proposal, and Dialogue Studies, undated (Box 42, Folder 539)
      - Publications and printed materials re. work with international students, 1960-1966 (Box 42, Folder 540)
      - Publications and printed materials re. work with international students, 1960-1966 (Box 42, Folder 541)
      - Reports to the General Assembly, 1959-1963 (Box 42, Folder 542)
      - Reports from ecumenical campus ministries working with international students, 1963-1965 (Box 42, Folder 543)
      - Reports from ecumenical campus ministries working with international students, 1966 (Box 43, Folder 544)
      - Reports from ecumenical campus ministries working with international students, 1966 (Box 43, Folder 545)
      - Staff section minutes, 1961-1965 (Box 43, Folder 546)
      - USCC Manual for Student Christian Workers on the Christian Ministry Among International Students, 1957 (Box 43, Folder 547)
    - Ecumenical International Ministries
      - Cambridge, Massachusetts: Harvard and MIT, 1959-1965 (Box 43, Folder 548)
      - New York, New York, 1966-1967 (Box 43, Folder 549)
      - Ohio State University, 1962-1964 (Box 43, Folder 550)
      - Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, 1965 (Box 43, Folder 551)
      - Purdue University, 1963 (Box 43, Folder 552)
      - University of Iowa, 1962 (Box 43, Folder 553)
      - University of California, Berkley, 1960-1965 (Box 43, Folder 554)
      - University of California, Los Angeles, 1960-1963 (Box 43, Folder 555)
      - University of Chicago, 1960-1965 (Box 44, Folder 556)
      - University of Michigan, 1960-1961 (Box 44, Folder 557)
      - University of Michigan, 1962 (Box 44, Folder 558)
      - University of Michigan, 1963-1965 (Box 44, Folder 559)
      - University of Southern California, 1962 (Box 44, Folder 560)
      - Washington, D.C., 1960-1965 (Box 44, Folder 561)
      - Washington, D.C., 1965-1966 (Box 44, Folder 562)
      - Yale University, 1963 (Box 44, Folder 563)
  - Committee on Program and Study Secretaries
    The Committee on Program and Study Secretaries took over for the Committee on Ecumenical Study and Strategy. Membership consisted of the General Secretary of NSCF, and staff from each member movement and board of missions involved with study and program development. As the NSCF did not have a study secretary, this responsibility rotated to different members on an annual basis. They continued the LMC emphasis until its end, and followed with a program theme focused on urbanization. Records in this subseries consist of correspondence, memos, minutes, reports, and publications that serve as research material.
    - Correspondence, Van Voorhis, Richard, 1963-1965 (Box 44, Folder 564)
    - Correspondence re. Communique, 1965 (Box 44, Folder 565)
    - Documents re. student mood including article Portrait of a New Generation by Harold Taylor, 1963 (Box 44, Folder 566)
    - Meeting attendance, October 1-3, 1966 (Box 45, Folder 567)
    - Memos and minutes includes directory, 1963-1965 (Box 45, Folder 568)
    - Publications re. issues in higher education including Community and Humanity in the University by Richard Schaull, Some Problems Facing Higher Education and the Role of the Campus Ministry in Confronting Problems Facing Higher Education by Ronald E. Barnes, 1965-1966 (Box 45, Folder 569)
    - Publications re. poverty and hunger including Poverty Amidst Plenty in America: Where the Churches Can do to Help Eradicate Poverty, 1965, undated (Box 45, Folder 570)
    - Report to the Fifth General Assembly, 1963 (Box 45, Folder 571)
    - Reprinting of WSCF study documents from the WSCF General Assembly, 1965 (Box 45, Folder 572)
    - Revolution and Renewal: Christian Response to the Technological and Social Revolutions of Our Time. A study book in the United States in preparation for a World Conference on Church and Society in Geneva, Switzerland, July 13-24, 1966 (Box 45, Folder 573)
  - Latin America Concerns Committee
    The Latin American Concerns Committee grew out of a concern over the Cuban Missile Crisis, and the United State's treatment of Latin American countries. Students wanted to open a dialogue with Latin American countries to explain that there were other views present in the United States. Materials in this collection contain promotional materials for a seminar, minutes, and papers.
    - Flyer and registration form from the WSCF Conference "Men, Ideas, and Action in the Latin American Revolution, 1965 (Box 45, Folder 574)
    - Minutes, 1965-1966 (Box 45, Folder 575)
    - Miscellaneous papers including statement written by the NSCF Latin America Concerns Committee re. the revolt in the Dominican Republic. Also a report The Christian Student Work in Puerto Rico Under the Council of Churches by the Student Work Office of the Council of Churches of Puerto Rico and a memo proposal for a national conference on the right to dissent from governmental policy., 1961, 1965, undated (Box 45, Folder 576)
  - South Africa Concerns Committee
    The South Africa Concerns Committee was created when the student focus shifted from Civil Rights in the United States to apartheid in South Africa. Materials in this subseries contains memos and reports.
    - Materials from other organizations such as reports from WSCF and the World Council of Churches. Also, includes newsletter South Africa Bulletin published by the American Committee on Africa, 1960, 1964-1965, undated (Box 45, Folder 577)
    - Memos and reports, 1965-1966, undated (Box 45, Folder 578)
- Conferences, Series IX
  The Conference series is divided into six subseries: General Assemblies, 19th Ecumenical Student Conference, Christianity and the Law Conference, WSCF Latin America Conference, WSCF North American Faculty Staff Conference, and Other Conferences. The subseries General Assemblies includes seven subseries for General Assemblies I through VII. All records arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - General Assemblies
    - General Assembly I, Oberlin, Ohio, September 5-11, 1959
      - Actions of the constituting General Assembly (Box 45, Folder 579)
      - By laws and constitution of the NSCF (Box 45, Folder 580)
      - Reports to the General Assembly (Box 45, Folder 581)
      - Schedule of events and working papers (Box 45, Folder 582)
      - WSCF minutes and reports (Box 45, Folder 583)
    - General Assembly II, University of Denver, Denver, Colorado, September 5-10, 1960
      - Civil Rights documents and statements (Box 45, Folder 584)
      - Drafts of reports (Box 45, Folder 585)
      - Ecumenical Development Among Christian Students: a Report of the General Secretary of the NSCF, 1960-1961 (Box 45, Folder 586)
      - Progress report on a Study of Christian Work Among Orthodox Students in the U.S. by Constantine H. Kallaur (Box 45, Folder 587)
      - Report on Budget and Finance matters to the General Assembly (Box 46, Folder 588)
      - Report of the Hearing Groups on Commission on World Mission and Committee on Ecumenical Studies and Strategy (Box 46, Folder 589)
      - Reports to and actions by the NSCF II General Assembly on the Commission on World Mission (Box 46, Folder 590)
      - Reports and Minutes of the II General Assembly of the NSCF (Box 46, Folder 591)
      - Working papers re. Life and Mission of the Church program, Commission on World Mission, Committee on Ecumenical Voluntary Service Projects, etc. (Box 46, Folder 592)
      - Worship program (Box 46, Folder 593)
    - General Assembly III, Conference Point Camp, Williams Bay, Wisconsin, September 3-10, 1961
      - Actions of the National Council of the YMCA's Regarding Relationship to WSCF and NSCF (Box 46, Folder 594)
      - Correspondence re. stewards for the General Assembly (Box 46, Folder 595)
      - Member organization reports that describe program and function (Box 46, Folder 596)
      - Memos (Box 46, Folder 597)
      - Proposal Concerning Cooperating Between the National Student Christian Federation and the Ecumenical Institute in Evanston, Illinois (Box 46, Folder 598)
      - Reactions to the NSCF constitution (Box 46, Folder 599)
      - Report of the General Secretary to the NSCF (Box 46, Folder 600)
      - Reports of Committees to the General Assembly (Box 46, Folder 601)
      - Report on the Student Non-Violent Movement by traveling secretary for NSCF, Jim Monsonis (Box 46, Folder 602)
      - Schedule of study and strategy group assignments (Box 46, Folder 603)
      - Some Thoughts about the NSCF as Community and as Organization by Herluf Jensen (Box 46, Folder 604)
      - Worship program (Box 46, Folder 605)
    - General Assembly IV, Conference Point Camp, Williams Bay, Wisconsin, September 5-12, 1962
      - Amendments to NSCF by laws and constitution (Box 46, Folder 606)
      - Correspondence and memos re. CWM delegates (Box 46, Folder 607)
      - Documents re. Commission on Ecumenical Studies and Strategy and the Intermovement Council (Box 46, Folder 608)
      - Memos (Box 46, Folder 609)
      - Notes of Richard Van Voorhis (Box 46, Folder 610)
      - Proposed budget (Box 47, Folder 611)
      - Report from the Latin American discussion group (Box 47, Folder 612)
      - Report on the workshop "Toward a Dialogue with China." Workshop sponsored by the East-West Contacts Subcommittee of the Young Friends Committee of North America. (Box 47, Folder 613)
      - Reports and Minutes from the IV General Assembly of the NSCF (Box 47, Folder 614)
      - Reports of committees to the General Assembly (Box 47, Folder 615)
      - A Service of Installation for the Central Committee Members of the NSCF and The Common Meeting (Box 47, Folder 616)
    - General Assembly V, Chicago Theological Seminary, Chicago, Illinois, September 5-11, 1963
      - Actions taken at the V NSCF General Assembly (Box 47, Folder 617)
      - Advance registrations and invitations (Box 47, Folder 618)
      - Correspondence re. conference leadership and planning (Box 47, Folder 619)
      - Memo and draft of schedule (Box 47, Folder 620)
      - Minutes and Appendices of the General Assembly of the NSCF (Box 47, Folder 621)
      - Participants in the General Assembly (Box 47, Folder 622)
      - Race and Civil Rights reports (Box 47, Folder 623)
      - Registration fees and receipts (Box 47, Folder 623a)
      - Report of General Secretary and report of the NSCF President to V General Assembly (Box 47, Folder 624)
      - Report on Alaskan Student Christian Movement Conference (Box 47, Folder 625)
      - Reports of hearing groups re. CEVSP, CWAI, and CPPS (Box 47, Folder 626)
      - Reports of committees to the General Assembly (Box 47, Folder 627)
      - Resolutions About Race Passed at the V General Assembly of the NSCF (Box 47, Folder 628)
      - The Role of the WSCF in the Life of the National SCMs (Box 47, Folder 629)
      - Summary Report on Consultation on Peace and Disarmament (Box 47, Folder 630)
      - Worship program (Box 47, Folder 631)
    - General Assembly VI, George Williams College, Chicago, Illinois, September 6-11, 1964
      - "The Catholic Student Movement and Hopes for Ecumenics" by John Donahue of Maryknoll Seminary (paper) (Box 48, Folder 632)
      - Christian Peace Concern Committee (Box 48, Folder 633)
      - Civil Rights and Race Issues: Reports an papers (Box 48, Folder 634)
      - Correspondence re. location (Box 48, Folder 635)
      - Credentials report (Box 48, Folder 636)
      - Delegate information (Box 48, Folder 637)
      - Hearing groups (Box 48, Folder 638)
      - Items adopted at the VI NSCF General Assembly (Box 48, Folder 639)
      - Memos re. VI General Assembly (Box 48, Folder 640)
      - Minutes of the VI NSCF includes draft (Box 48, Folder 641)
      - News releases (Box 48, Folder 642)
      - Nominations to committees (Box 48, Folder 643)
      - Proposal for NSCF/WSCF Ecumenical Experiment (Box 48, Folder 644)
      - Proposed Amendments to the NSCF Constitution and By Laws (Box 48, Folder 645)
      - Reactions to Milan Opocensky's presentation (Box 48, Folder 646)
      - Report of Latin American Concern Committee and working papers on Latin America (Box 48, Folder 647)
      - Report of NSCF General Secretary to the Sixth General Assembly (Box 48, Folder 648)
      - Reports of NSCF Committees to the General Assembly (Box 48, Folder 649)
      - Resolutions passed (Box 48, Folder 650)
      - Second All-Christian Peace Assembly, Prague, Czechoslovakia reports (Box 48, Folder 651)
      - Some Proposals Concerning New Ways of Work in the NSCF (Box 48, Folder 652)
      - Worship program (Box 48, Folder 653)
    - General Assembly VII, McCormick Theological Seminary, Chicago, Illinois, September 4-10, 1965
      - Actions taken by the Seventh NSCF General Assembly (Box 48, Folder 654)
      - Addresses given at the General Assembly including "An Ecumenical Strategy for the NSCF," keynote address, and "A Wider Ecumenism." (Box 48, Folder 655)
      - Annual Report of the General Secretary of the NSCF 1964-1965 (Box 48, Folder 656)
      - Budget and CWAIS reports (Box 48, Folder 657)
      - Conference planning includes minutes of the Planning Committee (Box 48, Folder 658)
      - Correspondence re. location and arrangements (Box 48, Folder 659)
      - Credentials report (Box 48, Folder 660)
      - Memos and schedules (Box 48, Folder 661)
      - Minutes of the Central Committee (Box 49, Folder 662)
      - Minutes of the VII General Assembly of the NSCF (Box 49, Folder 663)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 49, Folder 664)
      - News releases (Box 49, Folder 665)
      - Observations and reports re. VII General Assembly (Box 49, Folder 666)
      - Suggestions from WSCF Political Commission re. Vietnam War (Box 49, Folder 666a)
  - 19th Ecumenical Student Conference on the Christian World Mission: For the Life of the World, Ohio University, Athens, Ohio, December 27, 1963-January 2, 1964
    - Accounts payable ledger (Box 49, Folder 667)
    - Addresses given at the conference by Ruben Alves, Kenneth Carstens, Bishop D. Corrigan, Makolm McVeigh, Milan Opocensky, and W. Bonar Sidjabat (Box 49, Folder 668)
    - Administrative Committee (Box 49, Folder 669)
    - Advisory Committee (Box 49, Folder 670)
    - Alphabetical list of conference participants (Box 49, Folder 671)
    - Appeals letter for funding (Box 49, Folder 672)
    - Biographies of interviewers (Box 49, Folder 673)
    - Biographies of speakers (Box 49, Folder 674)
    - Book store arrangements, lists, and recommendations (Box 49, Folder 675)
    - Budget information (Box 49, Folder 676)
    - Campus coordinators information (Box 49, Folder 677)
    - Communion information including The Liturgy of the Apostolic Tradition of Hippolytus (Box 49, Folder 678)
    - Conference Steering Committee minutes (Box 49, Folder 679)
    - Correspondence with Alexander Schemann re. lecture series (Box 49, Folder 680)
    - Correspondence re. articles for publicity. Includes publications. (Box 49, Folder 681)
    - Correspondence re. conference newspaper production (Box 50, Folder 682)
    - Correspondence re. conference planning (Box 50, Folder 683)
    - Correspondence re. exhibit "A Space Exhibit in Faith" by Mrs. Lynda McNeur (Box 50, Folder 684)
    - Correspondence re. missionaries as living group leaders. Includes biographies. (Box 50, Folder 685)
    - Correspondence re. prayers at conference (Box 50, Folder 686)
    - Correspondence, Schmemann, Alexander (Box 50, Folder 687)
    - Correspondence re. tactical group at University of Washington performing W.H. Auden's For the Time Being. Play included. (Box 50, Folder 688)
    - Correspondence re. thank you letters from attendees (Box 50, Folder 689)
    - Correspondence re. worship programming (Box 50, Folder 690)
    - Criticism of the conference (Box 50, Folder 691)
    - Directory (Box 50, Folder 692)
    - Executive Committee: Memos and minutes (Box 50, Folder 693)
    - Exhibits Committee: Minutes (Box 50, Folder 694)
    - For the Life of the World lectures by Alexander Schmemann and Philip T. Zabriskie (Box 50, Folder 695)
    - Forms (Box 50, Folder 696)
    - Hospitality Committee: Minutes and Ohio University publications You, the Coed: a Handbook for Women Students of Ohio University and You, the College Man: 1963-1964 (Box 50, Folder 697)
    - Interviews Committee: Correspondence, lists, and minutes (Box 50, Folder 698)
    - Interviews Committee: Mailing list and documents sent (Box 50, Folder 699)
    - Leadership at the conference (Box 51, Folder 700)
    - Living Unit Group and Study Leader information and materials (Box 51, Folder 701)
    - Local Committee: Minutes and maps of Ohio University (Box 51, Folder 702)
    - Materials for the conference including flyer, program book, and conference newspaper (Box 51, Folder 703)
    - Memos of M.O. Williams (Box 51, Folder 704)
    - Methodist representatives (Box 51, Folder 705)
    - Newspaper clippings (Box 51, Folder 706)
    - Newspaper clippings and reports re. conference (Box 51, Folder 707)
    - Photographs and negatives (Box 51, Folder 708)
    - Program Committee: Minutes and notes (Box 51, Folder 709)
    - Publicity Committee: Minutes (Box 51, Folder 710)
    - Questionnaire for Campus Coordinators (Box 51, Folder 711)
    - Recruitment Committee: Memos, minutes, and reports (Box 51, Folder 712)
    - Reporting and Reflecting on the Planning for the 19th Quadrennial Conference by C. Alton Robertson (Box 51, Folder 713)
    - Reports from conference attendees (Box 52, Folder 714)
    - Sample evaluations (Box 52, Folder 715)
    - Scholarship Committee: Minutes (Box 52, Folder 716)
    - Survey and preliminary report on the conference (Box 52, Folder 717)
    - Thank you letters re. conference assistance (Box 52, Folder 718)
  - Christianity and the Law Conference, March 3-5, 1961
    - Biography and photograph of William Stringfellow, 1960-1961 (Box 52, Folder 719)
    - Correspondence to delegates and interested parties, 1959-1960 (Box 52, Folder 720)
    - Correspondence with delegates and delegate list, 1961 (Box 52, Folder 721)
    - Correspondence re. financial contributions, 1959 (Box 52, Folder 722)
    - Correspondence, requests for Oklahoma Law Review, 1960 (Box 52, Folder 723)
    - Requests for preparatory literature, 1961 (Box 52, Folder 724)
    - Correspondence re. translation and publication of Ellul's The Theological Foundation of Law and Barth's Evang elum and Gesetz, 1959-1960 (Box 52, Folder 725)
    - Correspondence re. translation and publication of Ellul's The Theological Foundation of Law and Barth's Evang elum and Gesetz, 1960-1961 (Box 53, Folder 726)
    - Papers: Liberal Education and the Law: a Bibliography compiled by Charles H. Russell, Gospel and Law by Karl Barth translated by Charles A.M. Hall, and Christian Ethics and the Law by Harry W. Jones (Box 53, Folder 727)
    - Report of the Oklahoma Law Review re. Christianity and Law Conference from 1959 (Box 53, Folder 728)
  - WSCF Latin America Conference, Mexico City, Mexico, December 17-18, 1962
    - Correspondence re. delegates (Box 53, Folder 729)
    - Conference materials (Box 52, Folder 730)
    - Preparatory materials (Box 53, Folder 731)
    - Reports from the conference (Box 53, Folder 732)
  - WSCF North American Faculty Staff Conference, MacDonald College, Bellevue, Quebec, June 24-July 4, 1963
    - Account book (Box 53, Folder 733)
    - Correspondence re. finances including ledger sheets (Box 53, Folder 734)
    - Correspondence re. planning and follow up (Box 53, Folder 735)
    - Correspondence, Wing, John (Box 53, Folder 736)
    - Delegate list (Box 53, Folder 737)
    - Finances (Box 54, Folder 738)
    - Planning Committee: Minutes (Box 54, Folder 739)
    - Preparatory material of C. Alton Robertson (Box 54, Folder 740)
    - Receipts and ledger book (Box 54, Folder 741)
    - Receipts and vouchers (Box 54, Folder 742)
  - Other Conferences
    - Interseminary Movement Triennial Conference: Addresses presented at the conference, September 8-12, 1960 (Box 54, Folder 743)
    - Interseminary Movement Triennial Conference: Conference materials (Box 54, Folder 744)
    - Interseminary Movement Triennial Conference: Planning Committee (Box 54, Folder 745)